### Information Provided by You or Collected with Your Permission.

* User Data: We may collect demographic data and information about your interests to help us understand what content you might be interested in. When you set up your own account or otherwise interact with our Services, we may also collect certain personal information that can be used to identify you, which may include your name, your e-mail address, your profile image and other information.
* SNS Data: We may allow you to use certain social networking services (**"SNS"**) via the Services and may collect information about you from that SNS that you have made available via your privacy settings. For example, if you link your Twitter account to SmartNews and let us know that you want to see what news stories the people you follow on Twitter are sharing, the links to these news stories will be sent to you via our Services. Please refer to the privacy policy for the SNS you use for more information on how your information will be shared by the SNS and information available on your SNS accounts.
* Interactive Features: We may offer interactive features, including features that let you submit User Content. We and other individuals who use our Services may collect the information you submit or make available through our interactive features. Any information shared on the public sections of these channels will be considered “public” and will not be subject to the privacy protections referenced herein.
* Survey Data: We may contact you to participate in surveys. If you decide to participate, you may be asked to provide certain information that may include personal information.

### Information Related to Your Use of the Services

* Device Data: We and third parties we work with may automatically collect certain data about the device you use to access our Services. This data may include your Internet Protocol (IP) address, mobile advertising identifiers (Google Advertising ID or Apple Advertising ID) and other unique identifiers, cookie identifiers, model name, operating system, country code, app version, and other user settings and preferences.
* Activity Data: We automatically collect certain data about your activities on our Services, including the pages, content or features of our Services you browse and the time you spend on those pages, content or features, the hyper-links from the contents displayed on our Services that you click on, referrer information and other information about how you use our Services.
* Location Data: You may, by your own choice, provide us with your location data such as your postal code, city and state information, or GPS location in order for us to display the weather, the local news, and the local advertisements to you. In addition, we may use various technologies to determine your approximate location, such as IP address and sensor data from your device that provides information on nearby Wi-Fi access points and cell towers.

### Information from Our Partners.

* Third-Party Partners: We may receive your information from our partners, such as publishers, advertisers, and third-party data providers. Our partners may provide demographic data and information about your activities and interests off our services, including information about your device, device identifiers, your precise or approximate location, websites and advertisements you interact with, your browsing patterns, and information about how you use our partner’s services.

How Do We Use Information?
--------------------------

Our primary purpose for collecting and using information is to deliver quality Content to you, our users. We also collect and use your information for a variety of business purposes, including:

1. To Provide the Services or Information Requested
2. To Measure Performance and Carry Out Research
3. For Customer Support
4. For Advertising Purposes
5. For Administrative or Legal Purposes

### To Provide the Services or Information Requested. This includes using your information to:

* Fulfill our contract with you;
* Tailor and deliver Content curated according to your interests which we infer from the data we collect;
* Provide access to certain functionalities, and features of our Services, such as the local news feature and the weather forecast feature;
* Create and update your account; and
* Manage your information.

### To Measure Performance and Carry Out Research. This includes using your information to:

* Measure interest and engagement in the Services;
* Pursue our legitimate interests, such as research and development (including marketing research), network and information security, and fraud prevention;
* Improve our products and Services;
* Develop new products and services; and
* Carry out analytics. For example, we may use personal information and other data to create de-identified and aggregated information, such as de-identified demographic information, de-identified location information, information about the computer or device from which you access our Services, or other analyses we create.

### For Customer Support. This includes using your information to:

* Respond to questions, comments, and other requests from you;
* Investigate and answer requests for customer or technical support; and
* Communicate with you about activities on the Services and changes to our Terms of Service.

### For Advertising Purposes. This includes using your information to:

* Tailor and provide personalized advertisements with you. We and our third-party partners may provide you with these materials as permitted by applicable law.
* Engage in cross device tracking, which helps us to track your browsing activity across different websites, devices and/or apps. For example, we may attempt to match your browsing activity on your mobile device with your browsing activity on your tablet. To do this, our technology partners may share data, such as your browsing patterns, geo-location and device identifiers, and will match the information of the browser and/or devices that appear to be used by the same user.

### For Administrative or Legal Purposes. This includes using your information to:

* Ensure internal quality control and safety;
* Verify individual identity to respond to certain requests or claims;
* Carry out audits;
* Prevent and prosecute potentially prohibited or illegal activities;
* Enforce our agreements; and
* Comply with our legal obligations. For example, we may disclose your information to certain government entities regarding certain claims or disputes relating to use of our Services.

What Information Do We Share With Third Parties?
------------------------------------------------

We may share the information that we have collected from you:

1. With Our Advertising Partners
2. With Our Service Providers
3. With Your Consent or at Your Request
4. With Affiliates
5. For Legal Reasons
6. In Connection with Business Transactions

### Information Shared with Our Advertising Partners.

We may provide information related to users to ad-serving companies, ad agencies, and other advertising partners (“Advertising Partners”) in order to deliver personalized advertisements within the service tailored to the interests of users and to measure the effectiveness of advertisements distributed within the service and distributed by Advertising Partners on other services.

When you use our Services, Advertising Partners may collect information regarding your activities and your device (e.g., your IP address, mobile device identifiers, page(s) visited, location, time of day). These Advertising Partners may use this information (and similar information collected from other services) for purposes of delivering personalized advertisements to you when you visit our Services and third-party services within their networks. This practice is commonly referred to as “interest-based advertising” or “personalized advertising.”

If you prefer not to share your personal information with our Advertising Partners, you may follow the instructions below.

We may use the information provided by our Advertising Partners regarding user behavior and user devices in conjunction with the user’s personal information held by us. This matching is performed for the purpose of delivering personalized advertisements to users and measuring the effectiveness of advertisements. We handle the matched information as personal information.

### Information Shared with Our Media Partners.

We have a number of media partners to provide quality content for the provision of the Services. To enable them to improve their content, we may provide the media partners with statistical information that does not identify individual users, such as demographic data and the number of page views of those who view each content.

### Information Shared with Our Service Providers.

We may engage third party service providers to work with us to administer and provide the Services. The types of service providers to whom we entrust information include service providers for: (i) the provision of the Services; (ii) the provision of information, products, and other services you have requested; (iii) analytics; (iv) marketing and advertising; (v) customer service activities; and (vi) the provision of IT and related services. For example, we use MailChimp to send you correspondence regarding our Services, including, without limitation, our promotional newsletters and e-mails. For more information, please see MailChimp’s privacy policy: [https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/).

We also use analytics services from Google including Google Analytics for Firebase to collect analytics information on the Services. Additionally, we use YouTube’s API Client in order to understand the content of YouTube videos to improve how we offer the Services to you. For more information about Google’s processing of your information, please visit: [https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites). To learn more about how to opt-out of Google Analytics’ use of your information on our website, please visit: [https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

### Information We Disclose with Your Consent or at Your Request.

We may share your information with third parties if you provide us with your consent or if you have expressly requested that we share your information.

### Information Shared with Affiliates.

We may outsource the handling of personal information to our affiliated companies in accordance with applicable law.

### Information Disclosed for Legal Reasons.

We cooperate with government and law enforcement officials or private parties to enforce and comply with the law. We may disclose any information about you to government or law enforcement officials or private parties as we, in our sole discretion, believe necessary or appropriate: (i) to respond to claims, legal process (including subpoenas); (ii) to protect our property, rights and safety and the property, rights and safety of a third party or the public in general; and (iii) to stop any activity that we consider illegal, unethical or legally actionable activity.

### Information Shared in Connection with Business Transactions.

If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, financing due diligence, reorganization, bankruptcy, receivership, purchase or sale of assets, or transition of service to another provider, your information may be sold or transferred as part of such a transaction, as permitted by law and/or contract.

Cookies and Third-Party Technologies
------------------------------------

**Cookies and Pixel Tags.** We may use cookies, pixel tags, and other similar technologies. Cookies are small text files placed in device browsers that store preferences and facilitate and enhance your experience. A pixel tag (also known as a web beacon) is a piece of code embedded in our Services that collects information about engagement on our Services. We may also include web beacons in e-mails to understand whether messages have been opened, acted on, or forwarded.

Our use of cookies and similar technologies falls into the following general categories: (i) operationally necessary; (ii) performance-related; (iii) functionality-related; and (iv) advertising-related.

**Software Development Kits.** We may use third party software development kits (“**SDKs**”) as part of the functionality of our App. SDKs typically collect your mobile device identifier and information related to your use of the Services. SDKs may allow third parties including analytics and advertising partners to collect your information for various purposes including to provide analytics services and personalized advertising. For more information about the SDKs we use, please contact us as set forth below.

Your Choices
------------

**General.** You may have the right to opt out of certain uses of your information.

**Email Communications.** If you receive an unwanted email from us, you can use the unsubscribe link found at the bottom of the email to opt out of receiving future emails. Note that you will continue to receive transaction-related emails regarding products or Services you have requested. We may also send you certain non-promotional communications regarding us and our Services, and you will not be able to opt out of those communications (e.g., communications regarding the Services or updates to our Terms of Service or this Privacy Policy).

**Mobile Devices.** We may send you push notifications through our App. You may opt-out from receiving these types of communications by changing the settings on your mobile device. We may also collect precise location information if you enable such collection via our App. You may opt-out of this collection by changing the settings on your mobile device.

**Personalized Advertising.** If you would like to opt-out of the advertising and other similar technologies (e.g., cookies) we employ on the Services, you may do so by blocking, disabling, or deleting them as your browser or device permits, including by following the steps set forth below. Please note that you can opt out of personalized advertising (i.e., targeted advertising), but you will continue to see non-personalized online advertising on the Services and/or other digital properties.

1. To limit ad tracking by Apple, Google, or other mobile operating systems: please follow the instructions for [Android](https://support.google.com/googleplay/android-developer/answer/6048248?hl=en), [iOS](https://support.apple.com/en-us/HT202074), and [others](https://www.networkadvertising.org/mobile-choice/). Other operating systems for mobile devices may also provide instructions on how to prevent the delivery of personalized advertisements.
2. To opt-out of the personalized advertising by certain third parties: please opt-out of personalized advertisement using your account settings on each applicable service. If you do not have any account on a certain service, you likely will not see any personalized advertisements from that service.

The online advertising industry also provides websites from which you may opt-out of receiving targeted ads from advertisers that participate in self-regulatory programs. You can access these, and also learn more about targeted advertising and consumer choice and privacy, at [https://optout.networkadvertising.org/](https://optout.networkadvertising.org/), [https://www.youronlinechoices.com/](https://www.youronlinechoices.com/) and [https://optout.aboutads.info/](https://optout.aboutads.info/).

Please note that cookie-based opt-outs are not effective on mobile applications and you must separately opt out in each browser and on each device.

**“Do Not Track.”** Do Not Track (“**DNT**”) is a privacy preference that users can set in certain web browsers. Please note that we do not respond to or honor DNT signals or similar mechanisms transmitted by web browsers when you visit our website.

Individual Rights in Personal Information
-----------------------------------------

In accordance with applicable law, you may have the right to:

* confirm whether or not we are processing your personal information;
* obtain access to or a copy of your personal information with accompanying details;
* receive an electronic copy of personal information that you have provided to us, or ask us to send that information to another company (the “right of data portability”);
* change, update, or correct your personal information;
* withdraw your consent to process your personal information;
* request that we restrict or limit our use of your personal information;
* request to opt-out of certain processing activities including, as applicable, if we process your personal information for “targeted advertising” (as “targeted advertising” is defined by applicable privacy laws), if we “sell” your personal information (as “sell” is defined by applicable privacy laws), or if we engage in profiling in furtherance of certain decisions that produce legal or similarly significant effects concerning you;
* request erasure of personal information held about you by SmartNews;
* object to our processing of your personal information; and
* appeal our decision to decline to process your request.

If you would like to exercise any of these rights, visit the "Settings" menu in our mobile application. Once you are in the Settings menu, click "Help Center." Once you are in the Help Center, the Help Center has a form for receiving inquiries. Please fill out the form with your inquiry or request. Please specify the nature of your request in the email you send. There is also a function in the Settings menu to delete or opt out of sharing your personal information with third parties that is used to provide account features and news feeds (see [here](smartnews://openDataControlSetting) for details). If you have any questions, please contact us as set forth below. Please note that there may be technical limitations that prevent us from fulfilling certain requests. We may carry out deletion requests by de-identifying and/or anonymizing information such that it is no longer personal information.

We will process such requests in accordance with applicable laws. To protect your privacy, SmartNews will take steps to verify your identity before fulfilling your request.

In order to verify your request, we use an identifier that is unique to your device that has been assigned by our App. If you submit a request in accordance with the instructions listed above, we will automatically receive the identifier. If we do not receive this identifier when you make a request, we will not be able to verify your identity and will deny your request.

If applicable laws grant you an appeal right and you would like to appeal our decision with respect to your request, you may do so by informing us of this and providing us with information supporting your appeal.

How Long Do We Retain Your Information?
---------------------------------------

We store the personal information we collect as described in this Privacy Policy for as long as you use our Services or as necessary to fulfill the purpose(s) for which it was collected, provide our Services, resolve disputes, establish legal defenses, pursue legitimate business purposes, enforce our agreements, and comply with applicable laws.

Supplemental Notice for California Residents
--------------------------------------------

This Supplemental Notice for California Residents only applies to our processing of personal information that is subject to the California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 (as amended from time to time) (“CCPA”). The CCPA provides California residents with the right to know what categories of personal information SmartNews has collected about them, whether SmartNews disclosed that personal information for a business purpose (e.g., to a service provider), whether SmartNews “sold” that personal information, and whether SmartNews “shared” that personal information for “cross-context behavioral advertising” in the preceding twelve months. California residents can find this information below:

| Category of Personal Information Collected by SmartNews | Category of Third Parties To Whom Personal Information is Disclosed to for a Business Purpose | Category of Third Parties Personal Information To Whom Personal Information is Sold and/or Shared |
| --- | --- | --- |
| Identifiers | * Our affiliates<br>* Service providers | * Advertising partners |
| Personal information categories listed in the California Customer Records statute (Cal. Civ. Code § 1798.80(e)) | * Our affiliates<br>* Service providers | N/A |
| Protected classification characteristics under California or federal law | * Our affiliates<br>* Service providers | * Advertising partners |
| Commercial information | * Our affiliates<br>* Service providers | * Advertising partners |
| Internet or other electronic network activity | * Our affiliates<br>* Service providers | * Advertising partners |
| Geolocation data | * Our affiliates<br>* Service providers | N/A |
| Inferences drawn from other personal information to create a profile about a consumer | * Our affiliates<br>* Service providers | * Advertising partners |
| Personal information that reveals a consumer’s precise geolocation | * Our affiliates<br>* Service providers | N/A |

The categories of sources from which we collect personal information and our business and commercial purposes for using and disclosing personal information are set forth above in “Information We Collect”, “How Do We Use Information?” and “What Information Do We Share With Third Parties?”, respectively. We will retain personal information in accordance with the time periods set forth above in “How Long Do We Retain Your Information?”.

The purposes for which we “sell” personal information and “share” personal information for “cross-context behavioral advertising” are to provide personalized content (including advertising), measure and analyze performance, improve the services we provide, and detect illegal or harmful activities.

### Additional Privacy Rights for California Residents

**Right to Opt-Out of “Sales” and “Sharing” for “Cross-Context Behavioral Advertising”.** California residents have the right to opt-out of the “sale” of their personal information and the “sharing” of their personal information for “cross-context behavioral advertising.” California residents can exercise these rights in the Settings menu of the SmartNews mobile application.

Right to Limit the Use and Disclosure of Sensitive Personal Information. California residents have the right to limit our use and disclosure of their “sensitive personal information.” California residents may do this by disabling our collection of precise geo-location via their device settings.

**Disclosure Regarding Individuals Under the Age of 16.** SmartNews does not have actual knowledge of any “sale” of personal information of minors under 16 years of age. SmartNews does not have actual knowledge of any “sharing” of personal information of minors under 16 years of age for “cross-context behavioral advertising.”

**Verification Process.** We will take steps to reasonably verify your identity before fulfilling requests submitted under the CCPA. As part of this process, we require that you follow the prescribed procedures to verify your identity unless the CCPA requires otherwise:

1. If you have your account, we will request you to provide your account name and your email address of your account, and a device token obtained from the Settings menu of the Services, or to log in to the Services via your account. However, for requests for the disclosure of specific pieces of personal information, we will request the submission of three documents (driver's license, health insurance card, passport, utility bill payment document, etc.) that can verify your personal information, along with a signed declaration under penalty of perjury that you are the person in possession of the personal information.
2. If you do not have your account, we will request you to provide multiple pieces of information that are known only to you (e.g., device tokens, recently viewed articles, locations where you have used our application, etc.) or sending a push notification to your device and requesting a response. However, for requests for the disclosure of specific pieces of personal information, we will also request you to follow the same procedure as set forth in (1) above.

**Non-Discrimination.** California residents have the right not to receive discriminatory treatment by us for the exercise of their rights conferred by the CCPA.

**Authorized Agent.** Only you, or someone legally authorized to act on your behalf, may make a verifiable consumer request related to your personal information. To designate an authorized agent and exercise any rights, please contact us as set forth below.

Our Lawful Basis for Processing Personal Information
----------------------------------------------------

If your personal information is subject to the EU General Data Protection Regulation or other related legislation, our processing of your personal information is supported by the following lawful bases:

|     | Performance of a Contract (i.e., to Provide Our Services to You) | Legitimate Interest | Consent | For Compliance with Legal Obligations |
| --- | --- | --- | --- | --- |
| To Provide the Services or Information Requested | ✔   | ✔   |     | ✔   |
| To Measure Performance and Carry Out Research | ✔   | ✔   | ✔   |     |
| For Customer Support | ✔   | ✔   | ✔   | ✔   |
| For Advertising Purposes |     | ✔   | ✔   |     |
| For Administrative or Legal Purposes | ✔   | ✔   |     | ✔   |

Links to Other Services
-----------------------

Our Services may contain links to other websites and services, including News Content. Any information that you provide on or to or that is collected by a third-party website or service is provided directly to the owner of the website or service and is subject to that party's privacy policy. Our Privacy Policy does not apply to such websites or services and we’re not responsible for the content, privacy or security practices and policies of those websites or services. To protect your information, we recommend that you carefully review the privacy policies of other websites and services that you access. Visiting these other websites or services is at your own risk.

International Transfer
----------------------

Your information may be transferred to, and maintained on, computing equipment located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction including, but not limited to, Japan, the United States of America, or other countries, where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. We endeavor to safeguard your information consistent with the requirements of applicable laws.

Our Policy Toward Children
--------------------------

Our Services are not directed to children under 16 and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under 16. If we learn that we have collected personal information of a child under 16 we will take steps to delete such information from our files as soon as possible.

Questions?
----------

Please contact us at privacy@smartnews.com if you have any questions about our Privacy Policy.

If you have a question about the SmartNews App, please contact us via inApp SmartNews Help Center.

SmartNews, Inc.  
144 2nd St, San Francisco, CA 94105  
CEO Kaisei Hamamoto

Last modified: January 1, 2024  
September 1, 2023  
January 31, 2023  
March 18, 2022  
November 1, 2020  
October 1, 2014
